Contact

8961888581 (Mobile) soura.poddar93@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sourapoddar (LinkedIn)

Top Skills CATIA V6

ANSYS 15

Java

Languages

English (Full Professional)

HIndi (Native or Bilingual)

Bengali (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Lean Six Sigma Green Belt Certification

The Data Scientist's ToolBox

Honors-Awards

East Zone Winner in Mahindra Design Quotient(2014)

East zone 1st Runners up in Design Quotient(2012)

7th out of 194 teams in Virtual-SUPRA SAEINDIA Student Formula 2014

7th out of 167 teams in Virtual-SUPRA SAEINDIA Student Formula 2015

Pranab Kumar Bhattacharya Memorial Award-2011

Soura Poddar

Consulting Intern-Deloitte USI || CNBC-D2C Top 100 Competitive Business Leader'20 || National Winner HUL Carpe Diem S6 || National Winner HUL Tech Tonic S1|| Treasurer, Exemplar Committee

Kolkata

Summary

Pursuing MBA BM from Xavier's institute of Management, Bhubaneshwar, Batch of 2019-2021.

3.5 years of experience in structural analyst role in Tech Mahindra. Part of design and development team working for fortune 500 clients across US, APAC and Europe.

Experience

CodeVector Labs - Al solutions Strategy & Consulting Intern July 2020 - Present (2 months)

Prepare business cases for AI implementation across all industry sectors.

Exemplar - Competitions Committee, XIMB & XUB Treasurer

February 2020 - Present (7 months)

Bhubaneshwar, Orissa, India

Deloitte India (Offices of the US) Functional Consultant April 2020 - June 2020 (3 months)

Hyderabad, Telangana

SAP functional consultant

Tech Mahindra

3 years 6 months

Senior CAE analyst

May 2018 - May 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Senior CAE analyst working on automotive, aerospace and Industrial products of Fortune 500 companies across US, APAC and Europe. Point of contact in

offshore location. Managed a team of 5 junior analyst. Extracting load values and deriving load conditions along with clients to perform structural linear, non-linear, fatigue, optimization analysis and suggesting design changes.

CAE analyst

December 2016 - April 2018 (1 year 5 months)

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

CAE structural engineer performing linear, nonlinear, fatigue and dubarility analysis on automotive and industrial products. Model meshing, deck preparation and generation of results to clients.

Associate Software Engineer

December 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 1 month)

Hyderabad Area, India

Associate software engineer working in FEA analysis of automotive components in part and assembly condition. Shell and Tetra meshing of cad models.

Steel Authority of India Limited

Project Trainee

June 2014 - July 2014 (2 months)

Presented a paper on Optimization of Load carrying capacity of with Improved Safety and maintenance of Haul Pack Dumper Trucks. Devised an improvement in the trucks to warn the persons operating, when the truck has been overloaded.

Biswa Bangla | A Govt. of West Bengal enterprise Summer Trainee-Agricultural engineering section(tractors) June 2013 - July 2013 (2 months)

West Bengal

Automotive Engineering basics, Internal combustion engine. Dismantling of IC engines, transmission set, suspension systems.

Education

Xavier Institute of Management

Master of Business Administration - MBA, BM · (2019 - 2021)

West Bengal University of Technology

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Automobile/Automotive Mechanics

Technology/Technician · (2011 - 2015)